When all else fails, they don't.
G.I. Joe: The Rise of Cobra is a adventure, action,
thriller film directed by Stephen Sommers.
From the Egyptian desert to deep below the polar ice caps, the elite G.I.
JOE team uses the latest in next-generation spy and military equipment to fight the corrupt arms dealer Destro and the
growing threat of the mysterious Cobra organization to prevent them from plunging the world into chaos.
Heavy Duty, played by Adewale Akinnuoye-Agbaje.
McCullen / Destro, played by Christopher Eccleston.
Storm Shadow, played by Lee Byung-hun.
The Doctor / Rex, played by Joseph Gordon-Levitt.
Ana Lewis / Baroness, played by Sienna Miller.
Scarlet, played by Rachel Nichols.
Joe: The Rise of Cobra is a 2009 American military science fiction
action film based on characters from Hasbro's G.I.
Joe toy line.
It is the first installment in the G.I.
Joe film series.
Directed by Stephen Sommers from a screenplay by Stuart Beattie, David Elliot, and Paul Lovett,
the film features an ensemble cast based on the various characters of the toy line.
The story follows two American soldiers, Duke and Ripcord, who join the G.I.
Joe Team after being attacked by Military Armaments
Research Syndicate (M.A.R.S.) troops.
Development for the first film began in 2003, but when the United States launched the
invasion of Iraq in March 2003, Hasbro suggested adapting the Transformers instead.
After leaked drafts of the script were criticized by fans,
Larry Hama, writer of the comic book series G.I.
Joe: A Real American Hero, was hired as creative
consultant, and rewrites were made.
Filming took place in Downey, California and Prague's Barrandov Studios, while six
companies handled the visual effects with Digital Domain as lead effect vendor.
Joe: The Rise of Cobra premiered at the Andrews Air Force Base on July 31, 2009, and was released in the United States on
August 7, by Paramount Pictures, following an extensive marketing campaign focused on the Mid-American public.
Despite mostly negative reviews from critics, the film grossed $302.5 million
worldwide against a $175 million budget, making it a box-office success.
A stand-alone sequel, titled G.I.
Joe: Retaliation, was released in 2013.
The film explores themes of government, technology, hostage, laser, warhead.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.